Saurabh Bajaj

saurabhbsd@gmail.com +91-8000888022

Summary

Saurabh is an experienced iOS application developer currently working in Pune, India. He likes to come up with simple solutions to difficult problems. Code quality, maintainability and pragmatism are his core programming principles. Being an iOS developer, he gives great attention to the UX and UI of the project.

EDUCATION

Master in Computer ApplicationsAug 2013 - Apr 2015University of Pune, PuneJuly 2010 - Apr 2013Bachelor in Computer ApplicationsJuly 2010 - Apr 2013University of Pune, Pune

CERTIFICATIONS

Diploma in iOS Application Development

 $June\ 2014\ -\ Aug\ 2014$

Sourcekode Technologies, Pune

Career History

Software Engineer 2 - iOS, Amura Marketing Technologies, Pune

Sept 2018 - Present

- Own the complete product life-cycle from design to implementation and App Store release management.
- Handle a resource and ensure timely development and delivery of application with minimal bugs.

iOS Developer, Promobi Technologies, Pune

Nov 2015 - Sept 2018

- Own the complete product life-cycle from design to implementation and App Store release management.
- Profiling and optimization to enhance efficiency and performance.

iOS Developer - Intern, Emerson Innovation Center, Pune

Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

• Worked on a Bluetooth based application in Objective-C.

Apps

Brew Survey: a mobile survey and feedback solution	[App Store Link]
Handwerker Station: an ecommerce app	[App Store Link]
Booster: a snapshot of your finances at your fingertips	[App Store Link]
Naki: an innovative tech based laundry service.	[App Store Link]

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C++, C, Python(minor experience)

Database: SQLite Version Control: Git

Libraries and Frameworks: Cocoa, AFNetworking, Fabrics (Crashlytics and Answers), Firebase, Alamofire,

CoreBluetooth

Mobile Development: Native iOS Development

Operating Systems: macOS, Windows

IMPORTANT LINKS

Github: https://github.com/saurabhbajajcode

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/saurabhbajaj02/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/saurabhbajaj91

Volunteering Experience

Volunteer, National level Conference: Sinhgad Institute of Management and Computer Applications, (Pune)

Feb 2015